# ALEKSEY POTAPOV

Senior iOS Developer

#### DETAILS

#### **ADDRESS**

Bratislava Slovakia

#### **PHONE**

+421949474199

#### **EMAIL**

ing.aleksey.potapov@gmail.com

## **SKILLS**

iOS Development: since 2012

Objective-C: 8+ years of professional experience

Swift: 6 years of professional experience

Familiar with: SwiftUI, Combine

Scripting Languages: Python, Bash, Ruby

Git and Gitflow for version control

Agile Scrum and Kanban workflows

Familiar with Java, Kotlin

Mostly used: Apple CarPlay, Core Location, Core Bluetooth, RxSwift, MVVM approach, Unit Testing, Dependency Injection

Mentoring and knowledge sharing

## LANGUAGES

Russian, Ukrainian (Native)

English (C1 level)

Slovak (B2 level), Czech (A2 level)

German (A2 level)

### **PROFILE**

I am iOS Developer with 7+ years of professional experience. I focus on the result along with a quality of code. I do mentoring for colleagues and perform internal workshops. I love simplicity and clean design, while covering code with tests and create reliable applications. I follow Apple Human Interface Guidelines to bring more benefits for users.

More info on my personal website: <a href="https://alekseypotapov.dev">https://alekseypotapov.dev</a>

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### iOS Developer, Sygic a.s.

Bratislava, Slovakia

Aug 2017 — Present

Sygic GPS Navigation app: implementing new features using Sygic SDK, RxSwift and MVVM architecture

Onlia Sense app: implementation from scratch till shipping using Swift, Firebase, Twilio, writing Unit Tests

Sygic CarNavi app: integrated Apple CarPlay, SmartDeviceLink and other 3rd party libraries for automotive

#### iOS Developer, Alice in Tokyo

Bratislava, Slovakia

Mar 2015 — Jul 2017

Internet of Things projects

My role: implement connection to smart devices on local network using Objective-C, Swift, ReactiveCocoa, Typhoon framework for Dependency Injection, Swift Protocol-Oriented Programming, Alljoyn framework

# iOS Developer, Mobindustry Corp.

Dnipro, Ukraine

Jun 2013 — Aug 2014

Outsourcing various projects using Core Location, creating user profile builder, custom iOS camera, custom UI elements

#### **EDUCATION**

Master's Degree of Applied Informatics, Slovak University of Technology in Bratislava Bratislava, Slovakia

Sep 2014 — Jun 2016

Bachelor's Degrees in Computer Science, National Mining University

Dnipropetrovsk, Ukraine

Sep 2010 — Jun 2014